SUMMARY

I bring a unique combination of coding and communications skills that I harness to create intuitive user experiences. I excel working with both programmers and non-technical audiences, with demonstrated project management and leadership skills. I am passionate about working with a talented & diverse group of individuals. I also enjoy learning about automation, the health field, and the future of the tech industry.

SKILLS

Programming Languages & Frameworks:

- · Frontend: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Backend: PHP, MySQL, C#/.NET, C++, Command Line/Unix, Git
- · Visualization/Animation/Design: Adobe XD, Balsamiq, Miro, Photoshop, Vyond

Project Management Tools:

- · Asana, ClickUp, TimeHero, GitHub, Slack, Discord, Google Suite, Microsoft Suite, Notion, Zapier
- Agile/Scrum Methodologies

Other Skills:

- · Leadership, Management, Communication, Problem-solving, Customer Service, Interpersonal, Computer
- Coaching, Attention-to-detail, Sales, Marketing, SEO, Documentation, Professionalism

EXPERIENCE

2023 - Present Certified Personal Trainer, Sports & Wellness

- · Programming customized workouts based on my client's needs
- · Lead and coach clients through exercises or programs
- · Encourage, motivate, and follow up with client goals and ensure progress is being made
- · Utilized my organizational skills and communication skills to drive successful results

2023 - Present Websit

Website Project Manager, Esparza

- Project-managed websites, landing pages, and internal pages from concept to completion.
- QA government websites for content
- · Maintenance multiple websites we hosted and ran security scans and updated plugins
- WordPress and Drupal websites experience using Flywheel hosting & basic Acquia hosting

2020 - 2023

Senior Strategist/Senior Specialist, Boomtime

- Responsible for maintaining websites, optimizing web pages/landing pages, performing advanced analytics, presenting strategic recommendations & tactics, and CRM automations
- Trained, managed, and worked well in a team environment, developing good interpersonal, written, and verbal communication skills
- Helped build templates using WordPress and used custom HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to build gift card pages
- Spearheaded local SEO projects and increased lead generation by 33%
- Became a reliable resource for SEO & SEMRush and saved the content team 1 4.5 hours per article helping with creating content briefs and performing keyword research
- Innovated and created onboarding training (videos & documentation) for new hires
- Advanced email marketing best practices, automations, and improved CTR and open rates

2016 - 2018

Web Developer/Freelance, Flek Development, LLC

- Responsible for the design and development of websites in WordPress
- · Project managed multiple websites and oversaw the websites from concept to completion
- Used PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to build custom, mobile-friendly websites

2016

Fullstack Developer Internship, Deep Dive Coding

- · Wrote code daily as part of 400 hours, mobile-first bootcamp focused on LAMP stack
- · Learned backend data design with MySQL architecture and object-oriented PHP
- · Built portfolio website and interactive public art web app from scratch

2016

Rural Sourcing Inc. Hack-a-thon

- Developed a custom web application, collaborating with a team in a high-stress, competitive environment
- Placed 2nd in the contest for presentation and creativity

Giles Sandoval

gsandoval2277@gmail.com | 📞 505.750.7722 | LinkedIn: gilessandoval | Github: gsandoval49 | Portfolio: gsandoval49.github.io

2013 - 2020 Corporate Wellness Director/Social Media Admin, Sports & Wellness

- Responsible for selling corporate wellness packages, family memberships, personal training packages and providing consultation/assessments
- · Promoted events within the club and on social media
- Trained a team of sales consultants & personal trainers in their marketing efforts

2012 - 2013 **Chef, Flying Star**

- · Provided friendly service and quality food to our customers
- Prepare and inspect quality ingredients for food preparation
- Adhere to safe food and sanitation practices

2005 - 2011 Store Manager/Co-Manager/Sales Lead/Sales Associate, Express

- Led and trained 400+ associates and 20+ managers at multiple locations, of which several obtained assistant or store manager positions within or outside the company
- · Achieved or surpassed quarterly store goals during employment
- Obtained strong interpersonal and communication skills to develop a diverse team and serve our customers

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

ABQ Web Geeks

· Attend weekly meetings to design, implement, and discuss software solutions for various projects

Volunteer Firefighter

- Provided excellent patient care and communicated well with my team
- Supported teammates during emergency situations & coping with stresses in a healthy and meaningful way

EDUCATION

(In progress) Certificate - JavaScript and React Intermediate - Frontend Masters

Associate of Applied Science Degree - School of Business & IT - Central New Mexico

Certificate - Full Stack Web Development PHP, CNM Ingenuity - Deep Dive Coding Bootcamps

Certificate - Microsoft C#/.NET Web Development, CNM Ingenuity - Deep Dive Coding Bootcamps

Certificate - Google Analytics Certification - Google Analytics Academy

Certificate - LinkedIn Marketing - LinkedIn Learning

Certificate - Emergency Medical Services - EMT-B - Central New Mexico

Certificate - CPT: Certified Personal Trainer - American Council of Exercise (ACE)

Certificate - CPR & AED Certification - American Heart Association (AHA)

Studied: Front End Web Development Track - Team Treehouse

Major: Business - Entrepreneurial Studies | Minor: Music - University of New Mexico (UNM)